RESUME

Longe Oludotun Williams - Fullstack Software Engineer

Phone: +2348170096535

E-mail: oludotunlonge@gmail.com | https://ng.linkedin.com/in/oludotunlonge

Portfolio: https://dotunlonge.com/

Code Sample: https://github.com/DotunLonge/Very-Simple-API-Call/blob/master/index.js

ABOUT ME

My Name is Oludotun Longe, I have over 4 years worth of software development experience from working with two software development agencies based in Nigeria, two Silicon Valley startups and freelancing in general with work centered towards front-end development related milestones, occasionally creating APIs or contributing to a project's back-end with Node.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

• Blockchain: Stellar SDK, Web3.js For Ethereum

• Front End: ReactJS (Redux), HTML5, SCSS, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

• Back End: Node - mongoDB, GraphQL

• **Design**: Sketch

• CMS: Wordpress, Netlify CMS

MISSION STATEMENT

As a software developer, I strive to always create better, cost-effective and innovative solutions following the best standards and practices.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

SELA LABS - Sela Labs is an early stage enterprise blockchain & Al startup based in New York, USA.

• Software Engineer (Partly Remote): May 2018 - Present

FIREFLIES - A conversation tracking platform based in San Francisco, USA.

• Software Development Consultant (Remote): July 2018 - Present

SWIPE – Technology company that creates software solutions on behalf of their clientele, based in Lagos, Nigeria.

• Full Stack Software Developer: January 2018 – June 2018

PLANET NEST - Software firm providing solutions to startups and established companies., based in Ondo, Nigeria.

• React-Team Lead/Software Engineer: January, 2017 - December, 2017

FREELANCE

• Web Developer: 2014 - Present

EDUCATION

• The Bells University of Technology - Ogun State, Nigeria - Bachelor of Engineering - Electrical/Electronics Engineering - second class upper (2,1).

SELECTED WORKS

Linda Ikeji TV - Online Platform For Streaming Videos. - https://lindaikeji.tv

Lead React Engineer responsible for taking the product from design to development, i integrated APIs, optimized pages for speed, built a HLS streaming player, contributed to Node backend as regards video file uploading, optimization and processing all the while making sure the platform has a great user experience.

Sela Labs - Impact Project Verification Platform - https://sela-labs.co

Lead Web Developer responsible for implementing the visual elements that users see and interact with in the web application, coding out backend functionalities and consuming the resulting endpoints; i interfaced with various blockchains via their SDK.

FireFlies.ai - Note Taking Platform - https://fireflies.ai

Software Engineering Consultant, Implemented functionalities observable on the dashboard utilizing both google and outlook SDKs under a development environment utilizing the following technologies, MeteorJS, GraphQL and ReactJS.

CICO - Online Platform For Tracking Employee Time. - http://www.cico.io/

Sole Frontend Engineer responsible for building the web platform from designs, integrating API endpoints and creating an optimized user experience for a platform aimed at tracking employee time and utilizing that data to organize billing.

Planet NEST - Official Company Website Rebrand - http://www.planetnest.com/

Worked as the Sole Engineer responsible for creating a Re-brand aimed at communicating the vision, brand and services of a social enterprise trying to make a skilled Africa.

Investiv - Custom Website and CMS Integration - https://investivgroup.com

Built out a custom website from designs with react-static and integrated Netlify CMS.